你们知道这是最后一次我们以六个单身朋友的身份
Do you realize this is the last time we'll be here...
在一起吗?
...as six single people?
咖啡厅怎么了?
What's happening to the coffeehouse?
从现在开始，是你们四个好朋友 我跟我太太了
From now on, it's you four and me and the missus.
我的小女人，好老婆，老伴儿
The little woman. The wife. The old ball and chain.
-老? -你是年轻性感的枷锁
- Old? - The young, hot ball and chain.
-好多了 -我们得走了
- Much better. - We gotta go.
-去哪里? -我要去拿婚纱跟妈妈一起吃午餐
- Where? - Get the dress and lunch with Mom.
乔伊，你也要去跟“妈妈”吃饭?
Joey, you too?
不，我只是听到了“午餐”
I just heard "lunch."
对，我可以去，当然
Yeah, I can go. Sure.
事实上我很高兴他们离开了
Actually, I'm glad they're leaving.
有件事我得跟你谈一谈
I need to talk to you about something.
-什么事? -这或许有点吓人
- What's up? - This may be a little awkward.
如果你需要钱，时机真的不太对 明天晚上我得请128个人吃晚餐
If you need money, it's a bad time. I'm buying 128 dinners tomorrow.
不，不是那样的
No, it's not that.
我不是以你朋友的身份跟你说话…
I'm not gonna say this as your friend...
我要以莫妮卡大哥的身份跟你谈
...but as Monica's older brother.
-但你还是我朋友吧? -接下来的几分钟不是
- But you're still my friend? - Not for a few minutes.
-现在你还是我的伴郎吗? -不是
- Right now, are you still my best man? - No.
我还是可以叫你罗斯吗?
Do I still call you Ross?
你们要结婚了，我真的很高兴
You guys are getting married, and I couldn't be more thrilled.
但身为她的大哥我得告诉你一件事
But as her older brother, I have to tell you this:
如果你敢伤害我妹妹…
If you ever hurt my little sister...
如果你敢让她不快乐…
...if you ever cause her any unappiness of any kind...
我会追捕你…
...I will hunt you down...
会踹你的屁股
...and kick your ass.
什么? 我是认真的
What? I'm serious.
-兄弟，别闹了，我不是在开玩笑 -我听到你的话了…
- Dude! Stop it! I'm not kidding. - I hear what you're saying...
谢谢你的警告
...and thanks for the warning.
别客气
No problem.
我们又是朋友了?
Are we friends again?
对
Yeah.
你不会相信刚刚莫妮卡的哥哥跟我说了什么!
You won't believe what Monica's brother just said to me!
Friends S07E23-24 莫妮卡和钱德的婚礼
The One With Monica and Chandler's Wedding
你在做什么? 莫妮卡
What you doing, Mon?
我在列出，婚礼上可能会出差错的事情
I'm listing things that could go wrong at the wedding.
那样子我可以做好准备
So I can be prepared.
-哪些事会出差错? -到目前为止有婚纱忘了拿
- What are they? -So far, the dresses won't get picked up...
我的头纱不见了，或是我忘了拿蓝色的东西 （西方结婚的习俗，要有新的、旧的、借的、蓝色的东西）
...my veil gets lost or I don't have something blue.
那是我负责的事
I'm responsible for all those.
我得考虑所有的可能性
I had to go with the odds.
你们还记得之前我去试镜没有拿到那个角色的事吗?
Remember that audition I had a while ago and I didn't get the part?
-那个广告? -那部舞台剧?
- The commercial? -That play?
另一部舞台剧?
That other play?
-那部电影 -对
- The movie? - Yes!
那部狗会开飞机的电影?
The one about the dog who flies planes?
不，但我真的很伤心
No. But, man, that one hurt.
-这部电影是描述第一次世界大战的士兵，-哦，是哦
- This is the one about WWI soldiers. - Oh, yeah.
以前我们叫它“伟大的战争”
Back then we called it "The Great War."
它真的是大战
It really was.
他们录取的那个角色不演了！我今天就要开始拍戏!
The guy they wanted backed out! I start shooting today!
恭喜
Congratulations!
-今天有彩排晚宴 -我一定会赶过去的
- Today's the rehearsal dinner. - I'll be done by then.
喔，那么你去吧，你这个电影明星!
Oh. Then way to go, you big movie star!
待会见，我要去跟纳粹作战了
See you. I'm off to fight the Nazis.
等一下，乔伊，纳粹是我们在二次大战的敌人，不是一次大战
Wait, Joey. We fought the Nazis in WWll, not WWI.
谁是我们在一次大战的敌人?
Who was in WWI?
你说吧
Go ahead.
你要迟到了! 快去…
You're gonna be late! Go! Go!
谁是我们在一次大战的敌人?
Who did we fight in WWI?
-墨西哥? -对，非常棒
- Mexico? - Yes. Very good.
-嘿，乔伊，我们准备好了 -我也是
- Hey, Joey. We're ready. - Yeah, me too.
理查，我们准备好了
Richard, we're ready for you.
乔伊崔比亚尼，这位是理查克洛斯比 他要饰演文森
Joey Tribbiani, this is Richard Crosby. He's playing Vincent.
-我要跟你演对手戏？ -很高兴能认识你
- I'm acting with you? - Nice to meet you.
我不敢相信，这太不可思议了 你刚刚拿下奥斯卡金像奖
I can't believe this. This is incredible. You just won an Oscar.
不，我没有
No, I didn't.
我知道你有
I think you did.
我想三次我都输了
I think I lost, three times.
-饼干? 你要…? -不
- Cookie? Would you...? - No.
再过一小时我们就要正式开拍
We're about an hour away from getting the scene lit.
-你们能对一下戏吗? -没问题
- Can you guys run it a couple times? - Yeah, sure.
好了，我们开始吧
All right. Let's do it.
好了…开始!
And... Action!
-我们得找到其他士兵! -算了吧，他们已经不在了
- We have to find the platoon! - Forget it, the platoon is gone!
-什么? -他们都死了! 面对现实吧，东尼!
- What? - The platoon's dead! Face facts, Tony!
我们该怎么办? 我们没有援兵或食物
What'll we do? We have no reinforcements or food.
地下室有食物 有马铃薯和一些意大利面
There's food in the basement. Potatoes and some pasta.
等一下，乔伊，你一直在摸你的脸
Hang on. Joey, you keep touching your face.
有什么问题吗?
Something wrong?
不，没有
No. No.
我以为这么做会很酷
I thought it might be a cool character thing.
他是个喜欢摸脸的人
He's a face toucher.
我可不那么认为
I don't think so.
我们从理查最后一句台词开始，开始!
Let's take it back to Richard's last lines. Action!
虽然我们没有武器，但我们还有食物
We may not have weapons, but we still have food.
马铃薯，意大利面…
Potatoes, pasta...
跟几罐金枪鱼
...and a few tins of tuna!
甜心，我们得走了
Honey, we gotta go!
这个问题真的很难启齿
Here's a question you never want to ask:
我爸能借用你的珍珠项链吗?
Can my dad borrow one of your pearl necklaces?
他有提到他的领口是哪一种的吗?
Did he say what kind of neckline he's wearing?
没有
No.
我只见过他一次，但我猜…
I just met him once, but I'm guessing...
是低胸的?
...plunging?
他是那种不招摇不罢休的爸爸
He is more of a if-you've-got-it- flaunt-it kind of father.
我去问问瑞秋有没有适合的项链
Let me see if Rachel has anything.
对，把更多的人扯进来
Yes, include more people in this.
你知道明天这个时候我们要结婚吗?
Do you realize that at this time tomorrow we're gonna be getting married?
我明天晚上有约了
I have a date tomorrow night.
-我不敢相信我们真的办到了 -别一副很讶异的样子
- I can't believe we made it. - Don't sound so surprised.
对不起，但是…
I'm sorry, but...
-没事 -什么?
- Nothing. - What?
哦，说实话吗? 自从我们订婚后…
Well, honestly? Ever since we got engaged...
我一直在期待发生什么事让你退缩
...l've been waiting for something to flip you out.
真的吗? 我也是
Honestly? Me too.
-真的吗? -对
- Really? - Yeah.
我以为会发生什么事，然后我会做…
I think that something will come up and I'll go all...
钱德会做的事
Well, Chandler.
-但什么事都没发生 -我很高兴
- But nothing has. - I'm so glad.
谢谢你在这段时间一直都非常地冷静
Thank you for staying so calm during this.
它让我非常地冷静
It's made me stay calm.
我可能会更差的
I could've been worse.
我马上回来
I'll be right there.
如果你在星期六前打电话来 这里是莫妮卡跟钱德家
If you're calling before Saturday, you've reached Monica and Chandler.
但如果你在星期六后打电话来，这里是宾夫妇的家
But if you're calling after Saturday, you've reached Mr. And Mrs. Bing.
请留话给…宾夫妇!
Please leave a message for... the Bings!
嘿，墨琳!
Hey, Maureen! Hi!
-她是我表妹墨琳 -我们是宾夫妇
- This is my cousin, Maureen. - We're the Bings.
嗨，你们都很漂亮
Hi! You guys look so beautiful.
宾先生跟宾太太
Mr. And Mrs. Bing!
莫妮卡
Monica.
你知道的，我以“大哥的身份”跟钱德谈过
So you know, I had my "older brother" talk with Chandler.
你说了什么?
What is that?
我告诉他如果他敢伤害你…
I told him that if he ever hurt you...
我都会追捕他 我会踹他的屁股
...I would hunt him down and kick his ass.
大家是怎么了? 我是认真的
What is the matter with everybody? I'm serious.
我会踹他的屁股!
I would kick his ass!
罗斯，拜托，我的妆要花了
Ross, please, my makeup!
-钱德 -妈
- Chandler. - Mom.
谢谢你记得穿…衣服来
Thanks for wearing... something.
我真的很兴奋 我以为我们害得你不敢结婚
This is so exciting! I thought we screwed you up too much for this.
你想想，很快地就会出现很多小宾
Just think, soon there will be lots of little Bings.
我不敢相信我要回去让人家喷口水
I can't believe I'm going back to work to get spit on again.
你很幸运，至少喷你口水的人都很有名
You're lucky. At least the people that spit on you are famous.
-谁对你喷口水? -我不想谈工作的事
- Who spits on you? - I don't want to talk about work.
宾太太? 他们是我爸妈茱蒂跟杰克盖勒
Mrs. Bing? These are my parents, Judy and Jack Geller.
-很高兴能见到你 -你是他妈妈还是他爸爸
- It's lovely to meet you. - Are you his mother or father?
杰克!
Jack!
怎么? 我没看过变性人
What? I've never seen one before.
爸，罗斯在那边 去跟他谈一谈吧
Dad, there's Ross. Go talk to him.
我甚至没办法假装我不会在意
I wasn't even able to act like I'm okay with it.
大家好
Hello, all.
嗨…爸爸
Hi... Dad.
嗨，宾先生
Hi, Mr. Bing.
-诺拉 -查尔斯
- Nora. - Charles.
-很高兴你们两个都来了 -对
- It's so great to see you both here. - Yes.
虽然有些人露的太多了
Although we may be seeing too much of some people.
你不觉得自己太老了 不该穿那种衣服吗?
Aren't you a little old to wear a dress like that?
你不觉得自己有阴茎 不该穿那种衣服吗?
Don't you have a little too much penis to wear a dress like that?
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
你当然可以踹他屁股，儿子
Of course you can kick his ass, son.
你想踹任何人的屁股都没有问题
You could kick anyone's ass you want to.
谢谢你们
Thanks, you guys.
-瑞秋? -什么?
- Rach, Rach? - Yeah?
快去跟钱德的爸聊天 别让他跟钱德的妈妈碰面
Talk to Chandler's dad and keep him away from Chandler's mom.
-但我不知道他长什么样子 -他穿着黑色裙子
- But I don't know what he looks like. - He's the man in the black dress.
嗨，我是瑞秋，莫妮卡跟钱德的朋友
Hi! I'm Rachel, a friend of Monica and Chandler's.
-我是亚曼达，-我懂了
- I'm Amanda. - Oh, I get it.
“男人，啊!”
"A man, duh!"
请大家听我说
Could I have your attention?
-我是罗斯盖勒 -罗斯盖勒博士
- I'm Ross Geller. - Dr. Ross Geller.
爸，拜托，我刚刚说过…
Dad, please. As I was saying...
我是罗斯盖勒博士
...l'm Dr. Ross Geller.
我是伴郎
And I'm the best man.
我得说，我有点吃惊大家今天聚在一起
And I have to say, I'm a little surprised we're all here today.
你们有人不认识钱德…
For those of you who don't know Chandler...
…他不是很喜欢谈恋爱
...he's not the biggest fan of relationships.
其实，在他遇到莫妮卡之前，我想…
In fact, I think before he met Monica...
．．他唯一真正的女朋友是一个叫莫莉的女孩
...the only real relationship he had was with a girl named Molly.
他本来要娶她的 但是她不能控制膀胱
And he would've married her, only she couldn't control her bladder.
那是他的狗．我说了那是他的狗吗?
It was his dog. Did I say it was his dog?
不管怎么样…
Any... Anyway...
这段婚姻对我来说有双重意义…
This marriage is doubly special for me...
不只因为新郎是我的好朋友…
...because not only is the groom my best friend...
更因为新娘是我的妹妹
...but the bride is my little sister.
她是所有男人梦寐以求的好妹妹
She's the greatest sister a guy could ask for.
请大家跟我一起举杯…
Please join me in raising a glass...
敬这对新人
...to the couple we're here to celebrate.
-敬宾夫妇 -敬宾夫妇!
- To the Bings. - To the Bings!
下次看到钱德你会走红毯，真酷啊?
How cool is it that the next time you see Chandler you'll be walking down the aisle?
真不敢相信明天过后一切都结束了
I can't believe that after tomorrow it's all gonna be over.
宝贝，不会结束的，你要嫁给钱德
Honey, it's not gonna be over. You're gonna be married to Chandler.
我可以穿万圣节的衣服!
Maybe I can wear the dress for Halloween!
我要去熨婚纱了
I'm gonna steam my dress.
谁负责确定它不会有问题?
Who will make sure nothing happens to it?
-我会负责 -谁要负责? 有人愿意吗?
- I'll do it. - Who wants it? Anybody?
-我说我会负责 -没有人吗?
- I said, I'll do it. - Nobody?
-好吧，那么我就自己来 -我不会搞砸的
- All right, I'll do it myself. - I'm not gonna screw it up.
你说的对，对不起，今晚你帮了大忙
You're right. I'm sorry. You were a big help tonight.
谢谢你帮忙将我奶奶安全地送回饭店
Thanks for helping my grandmother get to the hotel safely.
-当然，那就是我的工作 -好吧，对不起
- Of course! That's what I'm here for.- Okay. Sorry.
什么奶奶?
What grandmother?
-你跑到哪里去了? -我送我爸妈回饭店
- Where have you been? - Taking my parents to the hotel.
-你要回去工作了? -对
- Going back to work? - Yeah.
-很酷的太阳眼镜 -谢谢夸奖
- Nice shades. - Thanks.
我想如果我能戴上它拍戏 我的眼睛就不会喷到口水了
I figure if I wear these in my scenes, I won't get spit in my eyes.
如果我没有记错 雷朋眼睛是一次大战的官方赞助商
And, if I remember correctly, Ray-Ban was the official sponsor of WWI.
太棒了!
Great! All right!
-待会见 -好吧
- I'll see you later. - All right.
-钱德在哪里? -我想他在瑞秋的房间里
- Where's Chandler? - I think he's in Rachel's room.
钱德?
Chandler?
-莫妮卡在吗? -她在熨婚纱，怎么了?
- Is Monica here? - She's steaming her dress. Why?
-我想钱德走了 -什么?
- I think Chandler's gone. - What?
-他留下了这个 -告诉莫妮卡我很抱歉
- He left that. - "Tell Monica I'm sorry."
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
怎么了?
What's up?
“告诉莫妮卡我很抱歉”
"Tell Monica I'm sorry."
你自己去告诉她
Tell her yourself.
哦，我的天啊，钱德走了?
Oh, my God. Chandler just left, though?
或许事情不是我们想的那样 或许他是说：
Maybe it's not what we think. Maybe it's:
“告诉莫妮卡我很抱歉，我把牛奶都喝光了”
"Tell Monica I'm sorry I drank the last of the milk."
或者“告诉莫妮卡我很抱歉，我用她的镊子拔鼻毛”
Or "Tell Monica I'm sorry I used her tweezers to pluck my nose hair."
他做过的，我看到过
He does that. I've seen him.
或许他写这张字条告诉她 他改了名字
Or maybe he was writing to tell her that he's changed his name:
“告诉莫妮卡 我叫抱歉”
"Tell Monica I'm Sorry."
-这表示他吓得逃跑了！ -别那么消极!
- It means he freaked out and left! - Don't be so negative!
天啊，有没有可能“抱歉”现在就坐在里面
Good God, isn't it possible that "Sorry" is sitting in there right now?
菲比，我想罗斯说得对 我们该怎么办?
Phoebe, I think Ross is right. What are we gonna do?
我得去找他，把他带回来
I'm gonna have to go find him and bring him back.
你们别让莫妮卡发现这件事，好吗?
You make sure Monica does not find out, okay?
如果你没办法找到他，把他带回来…
But if you don't find him and bring him back...
我都会追捕你 我会踹你的屁股!
...I am gonna hunt you down and kick your ass!
我会找到他的
I will find him.
好了，烫好衣服了
Well, the dress is done.
什么事?
What?
我们都在替你高兴
We're just so happy for you.
你们真好!
That's so sweet!
我们来谈谈 明天我就要嫁给的那个男人吧
Can we just take a minute and talk about the man I'm gonna marry tomorrow.
我是说，我多么幸运啊?
I mean, how lucky am I?
好问题
That's a good question.
我只希望你们有朝一日也能找到像钱德那样的好男人
I just hope that someday you guys find someone like Chandler.
我希望我们能尽快找到跟钱德一模一样的人
I hope we find someone exactly like Chandler and soon.
乔伊，你能跟我对一下台词吗?
Joey? Can you go through these lines with me?
哦，天啊，他们才帮我化好妆
Oh, man, they just re-did my makeup.
-只要对最后两页 -好吧
- Just the last two pages. - All right.
我发现照片了
I found the picture!
照片? 什么照片?
Picture? What picture?
我在你的背包里，发现了我太太的照片
The picture of my wife I found in your pack.
-你能把剧本放下来吗? -我不想
- Could you lower the script? - I don't want to.
我得看到你的脸，才能知道你的反应
I need to see your face so I can play off your reaction.
好吧，听我说
Okay, look.
我知道你的演技很棒 演过很多莎士比亚名剧…
I know you're great and play all those Shakespeare guys...
但你喷得我满脸是口水
...but you're spitting all over me, man.
-那当然! -你知道你会喷口水?
- Of course I am! - You know you've been spitting?
真正的演员都会那么做
That's what real actors do.
发音是好演员的标志
Enunciation is the mark of a good actor.
发音正确时就会喷口水!
And when you enunciate, you spit!
我不知道这件事
didn't know that.
谢了，好吧，看我的
Thanks. Okay, check it out.
照片? 什么照片?
Picture? What picture?
-甘瑟，你看到钱德了吗？ -不，我没有看到他
- Gunther, have you seen Chandler? - No, I haven't seen him.
-该死 -他明天要结婚了，对吧?
- Damn. - He's getting married tomorrow, right?
对，别担心，一切都会没事的
Yes. Don't worry. Everything's fine.
-明天婚礼上见 -我没有被邀请
- We'll see you tomorrow at the wedding. - I wasn't invited.
那么后天见
Then we'll see you the day after tomorrow.
妈? 爸?
Mom? Dad?
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我们想看看这里到底有什么特别
We thought we'd see what the fuss is all about.
-我知道为什么女孩们喜欢来这里 -为什么?
- I see why the girls like coming here. - Why?
为了吧台后面那个性感金发帅哥
The sexy blond behind the counter.
-甘瑟? -她刚刚把他列入她的名单
- Gunther? - She just added him to her list.
-什么? 你的名单? -我们可以上床的对象
- What? Your list? - Of people we're allowed to sleep...
我知道那是什么样的名单
I know what the list is.
快坐下吧，喝杯咖啡
Come on, sit down. Have a cup of joe.
爸爸，我没空，抱歉
Dad, I can't. I'm sorry.
如果你看到钱德，告诉他我在找他
If you see Chandler, tell him I'm looking for him.
如果你看到丽塔莫雷诺（影星） 告诉她我在找她
And if you see Rita Moreno, let her know I'm looking for her.
开始!
Action!
我发现照片了!
I found the picture!
什么照片?
What picture?
我在你的背包里发现了我太太的照片
The picture of my wife, in your pack!
你偷翻我的私人物品?
You went through my personal property?
你的背包里为什么会有宝丽蒂的照片?
Why do you have a picture of Paulette in your pack?
文森，因为我们是爱人…
Because, Vincent, we were lovers...
两年了!
...for two years!
停! 太棒了!
Cut! Wonderful!
真的是太棒了!
Great scene!
你真的很棒，最后那一段 你喷得我的脸都湿了
You were awesome. In that last speech, you soaked me.
-这是明天的时间表 -明天没有我的戏份
- Tomorrow's call sheet. - I'm not working tomorrow.
-现在有了 -不，你得帮我这个忙
- You are now. - No, you gotta get me out of it.
我已经有计划了，非常重要的计划!
I have plans. Important plans!
-罗斯说还是没有钱德的消息，-天啊
- Ross said still no word from Chandler. - Oh, man.
但他们发现奶奶在第五大道上游荡
But they found the grandmother wandering down 5th Avenue.
好吧，至少找到一个人了
Okay, well, there's one down.
今天我要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
我断了一根肋骨，但我不在乎 今天我要结婚了
I cracked a rib, but I don't care. Today's my wedding!
我终于要结婚了!
My day is finally here!
或许她不会注意到他不见了
She might not even notice he's gone.
我要开始准备了
I'm gonna start getting ready!
我们不能让她开始准备，这太可怕了
We can't let her start getting ready. This is too awful!
但等她换上婚纱，而他又没有出现时…
But she'll be in the gown and then he won't show up...
这时候她得脱掉婚纱…
...then she'll have to take off the gown...
冷静点，你不能在这时抓狂
Stop it. You can't do this here.
对不起，抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
那真的是太悲伤了
It's just so sad.
振作一点，别让她看到你这个样子
Pull it together. She can't see you like this.
-她会发现不对劲的 -我知道，天啊!
- She'll know something's wrong. - I know. I know. Oh, God!
没有面纸了
There's no tissue.
你能拿张卫生纸给我吗?
Can you grab me some toilet paper?
喔，卫生纸也没有了 这里是莫妮卡的浴室吧？
Oh, that's gone too. This is Monica's bathroom, right?
-我找到一张了 -好吧
- I found one. - Okay.
-拿去吧 -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
噢，天啊
Oh, God.
能再给我一张吗?
Can I have another one?
没问题
Sure.
你需要牙线吗?
Do you need some floss?
我无法想像如果他不出现会发生什么事
I can't imagine what will happen if he doesn't show up.
这里有一大堆卫生纸
Here's a whole bunch.
她会在礼堂等他…
She'll be at the wedding waiting...
大家会说“哦，那个可怜的女孩”
...and people will be whispering, "Oh, that poor girl."
然后她得回来这里独自一个人生活
Then she'll have to come back here and live alone.
-哦，我的天啊 -什么?
- Oh, my God. - What?
垃圾桶有一根验孕棒 是阳性反应
There was a pregnancy test in the garbage. And it's positive.
莫妮卡怀孕了
Monica's pregnant.
我猜她不会是一个人了
So I guess she won't be totally alone.
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
我知道，莫妮卡怀孕了!
I know. Monica's gonna have a baby!
这能算是她的“新的东西”吗? （西方结婚的习俗，要有新的、旧的、借的、蓝色的东西）
Can this count as her "something new"?
我的天
Oh, my God.
你觉得这就是钱德逃婚的原因吗?
Do you think this is why Chandler took off?
她应该是刚刚才验的孕 我昨晚倒过垃圾
She had to have just taken that test. I took out the trash last night.
这将会是有史以来最糟糕的一场婚礼
It's turning into the worst wedding ever.
新娘怀孕，新郎逃婚，我还拿着这个
The bride's pregnant, the groom's missing and I'm still holding this.
菲比，我们不能告诉任何人这件事
Phoebe, we cannot tell anyone about this.
-对，没错 -好吗?
- Right. Yeah. - Okay?
嘿，等一下，你知道她用哪种方法避孕吗?
Hey, wait. Do you know what kind of birth control she uses?
不知道，怎么了?
No. Why?
为了将来准备，广告上可不会提这种事
Just for the future. This is hardly a commercial for it.
有消息吗?
Anything?
不，我跟在片场的乔伊谈过 他也没有他的消息
No. I talked to Joey on the set. He hasn't heard from him.
我又去问了钱德的父母
I talked to Chandler's parents again.
你说他失踪了?
You said he was missing?
不，我装作打电话过去跟他们聊天
No. I made it seem like I called to chat.
我很确定他们两个都以为我对他们有兴趣
Pretty sure they both think I'm interested in them.
-我们得告诉她他失踪了 -不，我们不能那么做
- We've got to tell her he's gone. - No, we can't.
她很快就会开始做准备
She'll start getting ready soon.
你不能拖延她吗? 我会把昨晚找过的地方再找一遍
Can't you stall her? I'll go back to the places I went last night.
我们还有多少时间?
How much time?
她最晚要什么时候开始准备?
How long before she absolutely has to start getting ready?
-顶多一小时 -给我两小时
- One hour. - Give me two.
你干嘛问我?
Then why do you ask?
-祝我好运 -我跟你一起去
- Wish me luck. - I'm going with you.
为什么?
Why?
你累了，你找了一夜 很明显你不是找人专家
You're tired. You looked all night. And, clearly, you suck at this.
我有夜盲症
I have documented night blindness.
不，你没有!
No, you don't!
好吧，但我不是那么差!
Okay. But I don't suck!
待会见
See you later.
你知道该怎么拖延她吗?
Do you know how you're gonna stall her?
因为她对今天的安排失去了理智
Because she is insane about her schedule today.
-我会想出办法的好吧，-祝你好运
- I'll figure something out. - Okay, good luck.
我想我们得先开始化妆，然后再弄头发
I thought we'd start with my makeup and then do my hair.
好吧，但你开始准备前 我得跟你谈一谈
Okay. But before you do that, I need you to talk to me.
谈什么?
About what?
我永远都没办法结婚了
I'm never gonna get married!
你会的，你的真命天子快出现了
You will. The right guy's just around the corner.
好吧，我们谈完了吗?
Okay, are we done with that?
不，我是认真的
No, I'm serious.
或许我该忘了这件事，当个女同性恋
Maybe I should just forget about it. Become a lesbian or something.
跟你在一起的女人是个幸运儿
Any woman would be lucky to have you.
或许我跟乔伊上床就不会感觉那么糟糕
Maybe I'd feel better if I slept with Joey.
瑞秋，你没事吧?
Rachel? Are you okay?
对不起，艾朗，我对通告表有点问题
Excuse me, Aaron? I have a little problem with the schedule.
今天本来没有我的戏 我非去参加一场婚礼不可
I wasn't supposed to work today. I have a wedding that I have to be at.
我最好的朋友要结婚 我是证婚人…
It's my best friend's and I'm officiating...
我真的四点前就得离开
...so I really can't work past 4.
你得待到戏拍完 我们不能为你暂停拍戏
You've gotta stay until the end. We can't stop filming just for you.
又不是你要结婚
It's not like it's your wedding.
那是我的婚礼
It is my wedding.
我没说清楚吗?
Did I not make that clear?
你说你最好的朋友要结婚
You said your best friend is getting married.
没错，和我结婚
Yeah, to me.
我和最好的朋友结婚 是不是很棒啊?
Yeah, I'm marrying my best friend. Isn't that beautiful?
-但是你说你是证婚人 -没错
- But you said you were officiating. - Yeah.
-你自己的婚礼? -很多你想不到的事情
- Your own wedding? - Happens more than you think.
对不起，乔伊，还是不行
I'm sorry, Joey. It's still no.
我要动手术
I'm having surgery.
什么?
What?
我骗你说我要结婚 因为我不希望你担心
I made up the stuff about the wedding because I didn't want you to worry.
但今天我要动手术
But I'm having surgery today.
什么样的手术?
What kind of surgery?
移植手术
Transplant.
但星期一你还得拍戏
But you're supposed to work on Monday.
毛发移植手术
Hair transplant.
但你不是秃头
But you're not bald.
要移植的部位不是我的头
It's not on my head.
我真的帮不上忙 或许你可以在四点前离开
There's nothing I can do.You'll probably be out by 4 anyway.
我们只要拍一场戏 就你跟理查，他是专业演员
We've just got one short scene, it's just you and Richard and he's a pro.
没问题的
You'll be fine.
早安，理查
Morning, Richard.
你来了! 太棒了! 我们开始吧
Hey, you're here! Great! Let's go, buddy!
我们还得拍戏!
We got a scene to shoot!
我系了两条皮带
I'm wearing two belts.
-你喝醉了吗? -没有
- Are you drunk? - No.
你喝醉了!
Yes, you are!
好吧
All right.
我们找不到他了 在这个大城市里
We are never gonna find him. He's one guy in a huge city.
噢，我的天哪，是他吗?
Oh, my God. Is that him?
那是一个中国老太太
That is an old Chinese woman.
他可能伪装了，你知道的
He could be in disguise, you know.
你知道吗? 你是对的，完全正确
You know what? You're right. You're absolutely right.
等一下
Wait a minute.
钱德!
Chandler!
现在你理性了
Now you're thinking.
可能我们完全搞错了
Maybe we're just approaching this all wrong.
如果你是钱德，而你想躲起来的话…
If you're Chandler and you want to hide...
哪里是别人想不到的地方呢?
...where is the last place on Earth people would think you'd go?
原来这就是你的办公室
So this is your office.
你们怎么找到我的 我就知道我该躲在健身房
How'd you guys find me? I knew I should've hid at the gym.
-你到底在做什么? -慌张
- What the hell are you doing? - Panicking.
我在上网找证据 证明我跟莫妮卡有血缘关系
And using the Internet to try to prove that I'm related to Monica.
-她还好吗? -她不知道你失踪了
- How is she? - She doesn't know you're gone.
她不必知道，来吧，我们回家了
And she doesn't have to know. Come on, we're going home.
-我不能那么做 -为什么?
- I can't do that. - Why not?
因为如果我回家 我们会成为宾夫妇
Because if I go home, we're gonna become the Bings.
我不能当宾夫妇
I can't be the Bings.
那有什么不对的?
What's wrong with it?
宾夫妇的婚姻都很可怕
The Bings have horrible marriages.
他们会吵架，打成一团…
They yell, they fight...
还会把救生员当成他们性爱游戏的玩物
...and they use the pool boy as a pawn in their sexual games.
你曾经穿上黑色裙子要我到你饭店的房间吗
Have you ever put on a black dress and asked me up to your hotel room?
-没有 -那么你不是你父母那样的人
- No. - Then you are neither of your parents.
不只是他们的婚姻 看看你的婚姻，看看大家的婚姻
It's not just their marriage. Look at yours. Look at everybody's.
只有保罗纽曼的婚姻幸福美满（好莱坞模仿夫妇典范）
Only Paul Newman can make marriage work.
我很清楚我自己，我不是保罗纽曼
And I've met me. I am no Paul Newman.
我不会赛车或做爆米花 也不会捐钱给慈善团体
I don't race cars or make popcorn. None of my proceeds go to charity.
听我说，钱德…
But look, Chandler...
现在没有人比我更看不起你
...right now no one has a lower opinion of you than I do.
但我完全相信你做得到
But I totally believe you can do this.
我也想，我很爱她，但我害怕…
I want to. I love her so much, but I'm afraid...
这太沉重了
This is too huge.
你说的对，这是件大事
You're right. It is huge.
我们为什么不一步一步慢慢来
So why don't we take it just a little bit at a time.
暂时忘了结婚的事，忘了它
Forget getting married for a sec. Just forget about it.
你能回家洗澡吗?
Can you just come home and take a shower?
好吧，不过之后
Well, yeah. But then...
我们只是回家洗澡
We're just gonna go home and take a shower.
那不可怕，对吧?
That's not scary, right?
那得看你说“我们”是什么意思
Depends on what you mean by "we."
-没错! -这就对了
- All right! - There he is!
老钱德会讲同音字笑话了
Good old Chandler with the homophobic jokes.
你意下如何?
So, what do you say?
我会洗澡，不过我不能保证任何东西
I'll shower, but I won't promise anything.
没事，我们就说这个好吗? 来吧，回家去吧
Okay, that's all we're talking about. Okay? Come on, let's go home.
谁是麦克・史密斯?
Who's Mike Smith?
我敢肯定这是我的办公室
I was sure this was my office.
漫漫长夜是最难熬的
The nights are the hardest.
但天亮了…
But then the day comes...
白天就跟黑夜一样难熬
...and that's every bit as hard as the night.
-然后黑夜又来了…-白天跟黑夜都很难熬，我知道了
- Then the night comes again... - The days and nights are hard, I get it!
我得开始准备了，今天我要结婚了
I have to start getting ready. I'm getting married today.
我知道，在黄昏的时候
I know. At dusk.
对我来说黄昏是很难熬的
That's such a hard time for me.
我要化妆了 我们得在一小时内赶到饭店
I'm gonna put my makeup on. We have to be at the hotel in an hour.
-等一下 -什么?
- Wait! - What?
我们去吃午饭吧!
Let's go to lunch!
我不能去吃午饭!
I can't go to lunch!
对
Right.
天啊，我跌倒了
Oh, good God, I've fallen down.
发生了什么事?
What's going on?
好吧，听我说
All right, honey, listen.
当我告诉你这件事时，我要你记得…
When I tell you what I'm about to tell you, I need you to remember...
我们都会支持你，我们都爱你
...that we are all here for you and that we love you.
好吧，你真的吓坏我了
Okay, you're really freaking me out.
我们找不到钱德…
We can't find Chandler...
的背心
...'s vest.
我们找不到钱德的背心
We can't find Chandler's vest.
怎么可能? 等一下，你是认真的吗?
How can that be? Wait, are you serious?
背心找到了
Found the vest.
我们得看好它，确定不会再把它弄丢了
We'll have to keep an eye on it, make sure we don't lose it again.
好吧，别那样吓我
Okay, don't scare me like that, okay?
刚刚我以为“天啊，最糟糕的事发生”
For a minute, I was like, "Oh, my God! The worst has happened!"
我宁可死去也不愿看到她回到你身边!
I would sooner die in this hellhole than see her back with you!
会解决的
That can be arranged.
-重来 -什么?! 他刺中我了!
- Let's reset. - What?! He got me!
重新来一次
Let's take it from there.
你今天心不在焉吗? 那样会很慢的
Are you a little off today? It's going terribly slowly.
我最好的朋友一个小时后就要结婚了，知道吗?
Look, my best friends are getting married in, like, an hour, okay?
我是证婚牧师．求你了，顺利完成好吗?
And I'm the minister. Please, can you pull it together?
当然．对不起，我不能让你因为我错过任何东西
Of course. I'm sorry. I'd hate you to miss anything like that on account of me.
-我可以做到的 -谢谢，谢谢
- I can do this. - Thank you. Thank you.
准备，开始
Still rolling. And, action.
我宁可死去也不愿看到她回到你身边!
I would sooner die in this hellhole than see her back with you!
会解决的!
That can be arranged!
这么滑的畜生!
Slippery little bugger!
你们两个结过婚是吧?
So you two were married, huh?
后来发生了什么事? 你们分开了吗?
What happened, you just drift apart?
还记得我们结婚那天吗?
Do you remember our wedding day?
你知道我和伴郎上床吗?
Did you know I slept with the best man?
当然，他告诉我了
Yes, he told me.
至少他是这样说的
At least I think that was what he said.
他的腿缠着我的头 所以很难理解他的话
It was difficult to understand with his legs wrapped around my head.
新娘来了
Here comes the bride.
我的天，莫妮卡
Oh, my God, Monica!
我想每天都穿这件婚纱
I want to wear this every day.
你真的好漂亮
You look so beautiful.
我为自己感到高兴
I'm so happy for me.
-喂? -钱德出现了吗?
- Hello? - Did Chandler show up yet?
-我们找到他了，没事了 -该死!
- We got him back. Everything's fine. - Damn it!
-你在哪里? -我还在片场里
- Where are you? - I'm still on the set.
不到一小时婚礼就要开始
The wedding is in less than an hour.
我知道，对不起，跟我对戏的演员喝醉了，戏没拍好他们不让我离开
I know. I'm sorry. The guy's drunk. They won't let me go until we get this.
我的天啊，我得再去找位牧师
Oh, my God. I'm gonna have to find another minister.
不，我是牧师
No, I'm the minister!
听着，叫他们两个一起听电话 我现在就帮他们证婚
Look, put them both on the phone, I'll marry them right now.
乔伊，我得挂电话了
Joey, I have to go.
别挂我电话，我现在就可以帮你跟我证婚，我有那样的权力
Don't hang up on me! I'll marry you and me right now! I have the power!
你看看，你穿上了礼服
There you go! You put on a tuxedo!
那一点都不可怕吧?
That wasn't scary, was it?
对
No.
我跟你说一步一步慢慢来
I'm telling you, just a little bit at a time.
接下来我们要做什么?
What's the next little bit?
结婚
Getting married.
你一定能办到 就像其他的事你都做得很好
You can do that too. Just like you've done everything else.
你说的对，我可以办到
Yeah, you're right. I can do that.
-我要出去一下 -你要去哪里?
- Excuse me for a minute. - Where you going?
我不会再逃走，我只想呼吸点新鲜空气
I'm not gonna run away again.I just want some fresh air.
-好吧 -好吧
- Okay. - Okay.
哦，新鲜空气
Oh, fresh air!
-帮我掩护 -或许你反应过度了 你可以做到的
- Cover for me. - Maybe you're overreacting. You do that.
我们得想个办法
We gotta do something.
乔伊没办法赶过来，我会看看饭店里有没有其他人在办婚礼
Joey won't make it, so I'll look around the hotel for other weddings.
别告诉他们莫妮卡怀孕了 因为他们厌恶那种事
Don't tell them Monica's pregnant, because they frown on that.
好吧
Okay.
安纳斯塔赛奇斯 巴巴西法奇斯新婚，太棒了（希腊人名）
Anastassakis Papasifakis wedding. Excellent.
恭喜
Congratulations.
恭喜（希腊语）
Mazel tov.
嗨，好漂亮的帽子
Hi! Oh, great hat.
我要你帮另一场婚礼证婚，可以吗?
I need you to perform another wedding. Can you do that?
我不知道，他们是希腊正教的信徒吗?
I don't know. Are they Greek Orthodox?
对
Yeah. Yeah.
他们是我的朋友 莫妮卡・史蒂芬・诺波里斯（希腊姓）
They're my friends, Monica Stephanopolis.
跟钱德・艾西多菲利斯（希腊姓）
And Chandler Acidophilus.
嗨。嗨
Hi. Hi.
嗨
Hi.
有人看到钱德吗?
Has anyone seen Chandler?
-我还以为他跟你在一起 -他刚才是跟我在一起
- I thought he was with you. - He was with me.
我们在玩游戏捉迷藏
We're playing a little game. Hide-and-seek.
你不能问我们，儿子，那是作弊
You can't ask us, son. That's cheating.
你说的对，谢谢你让我诚实，爸
You're right. Thanks for keeping me honest, Dad.
他最好别到这里来 他不能看到新娘穿婚纱的样子
He better not come here. He can't see the bride in her wedding dress.
我还记得我们结婚的时候 我看到新郎穿婚纱的样子
As I recall, when we got married, I saw the groom in the wedding dress.
那是婚礼后的事，应该不会带来恶运
That was after the wedding. It's not bad luck then.
亲爱的，那也没带来好运
Honey, it isn't good luck.
我的天! 莫妮卡
Oh, my God! Monica.
我知道
I know!
-钱德还好吗? -他好极了
- How's Chandler doing? - Great.
他非常好，别担心钱德
He's doing great. Don't you worry about Chandler.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
你出汗了
Well, you're sweating.
为你和钱德流的幸福汗
Out of happiness for you and Chandler.
这是快乐汗滴
These are beads of joy.
你真好
That's sweet.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
-菲比，我能跟你谈一下吗? -没问题
- Phoebe, can I see you for a second? - Yeah.
-发生了什么事? -钱德又不见了
- What's going on? - Chandler's gone again.
为什么你要跟一个可能会逃跑的人玩捉迷藏呢?
Why would you play hide-and-seek with someone you know is a flight risk?
艾朗，你得放我走 那家伙烂醉如泥
Aaron, you gotta let me go. The guy's hammered.
对不起，只要他还清醒地待在这里 我们就得继续拍下去
I'm sorry. As long as he's here and conscious, we're still shooting.
你该不会刚好有根大叉子吧?
You wouldn't happen to have a very big fork?
我刚刚跟导演谈过
So I just talked to the director.
就这样，今天就拍到这里为止
That's it. We're done for the day.
戏拍完了吗?
We finished the scene?
-你表现的很棒 -你也是
- You were wonderful. - As were you.
我把你的车开过来了 就停在外面
So I got your car. It's right outside.
为什么? 今天的戏拍完了吗?
Why? Are we done for the day?
你告诉我的呀
That's what you told me.
谢谢，别客气
Thank you. You're welcome.
不，我们得走了，来吧，要走了
No, we gotta go. Come on. Here we go.
那是我的屁股吗?
Is that my ass?
-他在那里! -什么?
- There he is! - What?
这次你逃不了，先生!
You're not getting away this time, mister!
除非你真的要我踹你屁股
Unless you want that ass-kicking we talked about!
罗斯!
Ross!
我是认真的! 我不准你抛弃我妹妹!
I'm serious! You're not walking out on my sister!
没错，我不会的
That's right. I'm not.
-那么你跑到哪里去了? -我知道莫妮卡的事
- Then where have you been? - I know about Monica.
-你知道了? -什么?
- You know? - What?
我听到你跟瑞秋说话
I heard you and Rachel talking.
-什么? 你说什么? -你不知道吗?
- What? Talking about what? - You don't know?
如果你们不立刻告诉我发生了什么事…
If somebody doesn't tell me what's going on right now...
怎么? 你会“嘿呀”吗?
What, you'll "hi-yah"?
莫妮卡怀孕了
Monica's pregnant.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我的天，你没有被吓跑吗?
Oh, my God. And you're not freaking out?
我是吓坏了，后来我去了礼品店 因为我的烟都抽完了
I was. Then I went to the gift shop because I was out of cigarettes.
-烟? -请谈正事
- Cigarettes? - Big picture, please!
我在礼品店看到这个东西
So when I was in the gift shop, that's when I saw this.
我想“能穿上这玩意的东西应该不可怕”
And I thought, "Anything that can fit into this can't be scary."
你明显地没看过《鬼娃回魂3》
You obviously didn't see Chucky III.
别这样，看看这件小衣服有多可爱
But come on, look at how cute and small this is.
我要把它送给莫妮卡，她会知道我没事的
So I got it to give Monica so she'd know I was okay.
兄弟
Dude.
做的好，儿子，我知道你一定能找到他
Way to go, son. I knew you'd find him.
我们的小儿子要结婚了
Our little boy is getting married.
看看你，真的好英俊
Look at you, so handsome.
你看起来很漂亮，妈
You look beautiful, Mom.
你看起来也很漂亮，爸
You look beautiful too, Dad.
我爱你们
I love you both.
我很高兴你们来了
I'm so glad you're here.
你是钱德吗?
Are you Chandler?
你是乔伊吗?
Are you Joey?
-这真的是太棒了 -什么?
- This is nice. - What?
这是我第一次走在红毯上 并知道自己不可能会离婚
I've never walked down the aisle knowing it can't end in divorce.
真希望你祖母能活着看到这一幕
I wish your grandmother had lived to see this.
-但奶奶就在那边啊 -不是那个老太婆，我是说我妈
- She's right there. - Not that old crone. My mother.
恭喜你，亲爱的
Congratulations, darling.
我们爱你，甜心
We love you, sweetheart.
你看起来好美
You look beautiful.
-这是那个“新的”吗? -不要在现在讨论
- Is this new? - Not now.
-他是谁? -我是卡拉巴索斯神父
- Who's this? - I'm Father Karabasos.
他是希腊正教的神父
He's Greek Orthodox.
你们是希腊正教的信徒
As are you.
开始举行婚礼吧
Let us begin.
亲爱的来宾…
Dearly beloved...
那是我的台词
That's my line!
我从这里开始接手，谢谢
I can take it from here. Thanks.
亲爱的来宾，抱歉我来迟了一点
Dearly beloved, I'm sorry I'm a little late.
或许你们会觉得很困惑…
You may be confused by this now...
但到了2002年阵亡将士纪念日（5月最后一个周一）你们就会了解
...but you won't be Memorial Day weekend, 2002.
快点开始举行婚礼 免得新郎又逃跑了
Let's get started before the groom takes off again.
今天我们齐聚在这里…
We are gathered here today...
参加这个男人…
...to join this man...
跟这个女人神圣的婚礼
...and this woman in the bonds of holy matrimony.
我跟莫妮卡及钱德认识很久了 我不能想像…
I've known Monica and Chandler for a long time, and I cannot imagine...
有谁比他们两个更匹配
...two people more perfect for each other.
因为我把演讲稿忘在更衣室里…
And now, as I've left my notes in my dressing room...
我们直接念誓词吧，莫妮卡?
...we shall proceed to the vows. Monica?
-他逃走了? -快点
- He took off? - Go on. Go on.
钱德，从小…
Chandler, for so long...
我就在想，我能不能找到我的白马王子
...I wondered if I would ever find my prince.
我的灵魂伴侣
My soul mate.
三年前，在另一场婚礼．
Then three years ago, at another wedding...
我向朋友寻求安慰
...I turned to a friend for comfort.
结果我找到了我一直在找的一切
And instead I found everything that I'd ever been looking for my whole life.
现在
And now...
我们在这里．
...here we are...
一起迎接未来
...with our future before us.
我只想跟你在一起
And I only want to spend it with you.
我的白马王子
My prince.
我的灵魂伴侣
My soul mate.
我的朋友
My friend.
除非你不愿意
Unless you don't want to.
轮到你了
You go.
钱德?
Chandler?
不，没关系
No, that's okay.
我以为这是我必须做的最困难的一件事
I thought this would be the most difficult thing I ever had to do.
但我看到你走过红毯时 我了解到它真的很简单
But when I saw you walking down that aisle, I realized it's simple.
我爱你
I love you.
无论出现什么样的惊喜 没关系，因为我会永远爱你
Any surprises that come our way, it's okay. Because I will always love you.
我注定要跟你共渡余生
You are the person I was meant to spend the rest of my life with.
你想知道我确不确定吗?
You want to know if I'm sure?
你可以吻新娘了
You may now kiss the bride.
我要以纽约州跟网友们…
I guess by the powers vested in me by the state of New York...
赋予我的权力…
...and the Internet guys...
我现在宣布你们结为夫妇
...I now pronounce you husband and wife.
等一下，你们愿意吗?
Oh, wait. Do you take each other?
-我愿意 -我愿意
- I do. - I do.
太棒了，你们都愿意!
Yeah, you do!
戒指
Rings.
哦，该死，好吧
Oh, crap. Okay.
来戴戒指吧
Let's do the rings.
可以吗?
We good? Yeah? Good?
我要再一次…
Once again...
宣布你们结为夫妇
...I pronounce you husband and wife.
你可以再吻新娘一次
Now kiss her again.
我爱你
I love you.
我知道宝宝的事了
And I know about the baby.
-什么宝宝? -我们的宝宝
- What baby? - Our baby.
我们有宝宝了
We have a baby?
菲比发现了你的验孕棒
Phoebe found your pregnancy test.
我没有验孕
I didn't take a pregnancy test.
那么是谁验了孕?
Then who did?
看看他们
Look at them.
他们要有孩子了
And they're gonna have a baby.